<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2016">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Bitnami. |">
]>
<chapter>
	
	<title>Bitnami ownCloud Virtual Machine: Deploying the application</title>
	<para>Thanks to the Bitnami ownCloud installer you can leave the ownCloud application deployed and ready quickly 
	and easily without having the need for special programming skills in Linux.</para> 
	<para>To deploy the application you need to comply with these requirements: </para>
	
	<note>
		<title>Prerequisites</title>
		<para>Docker Engine 1.1.0.0</para>
		<para>Docker Compose 1.6.0 or later</para>
	</note>
	
	<para>For this installation we are going to use <emphasis role="bold">Bitnami ownCloud Virtual Machine</emphasis> 
	which has Docker and Docker Compose already installed.</para>
	<para>These are the steps which must be taken to install the requirements and deploy the application:</para>
	
	<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
		<listitem>
			<para><emphasis>Import the Bitnami Virtual Machine into your hypervisor:</emphasis>
			It is compatible with Oracle VirtualBox and VMware vSphere, Workstation, and Fusion. </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><emphasis>Start the server and check its IP Address:</emphasis> this IP will be the IP of your ownCloud environment.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><emphasis>Add the IP Address and a sample host in your local machine:</emphasis> 
			thus the Docker container can talk with your local host.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><emphasis>Clone the bitnami-docker-ownCloud repository:</emphasis> in order to get both Docker Compose Tool, 
			Docker compose file, ownCloud image and its requirements.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><emphasis>Configure environment variables:</emphasis> 
			adding the IP Address in your Docker Compose file as envronment variable.</para>
		</listitem>
	    <listitem>
			<para><emphasis>Run the Docker containers:</emphasis> this step starts the creation of the containers and the 
			installation of the database, application and its requirements. </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para><emphasis>Access to your application:</emphasis> go to your browser and access 
			to your ownCloud application through the URL of the sample host or IP Address you have added in Step 3.</para>
		</listitem>
	</orderedlist>
	
	<para><emphasis role="bold">The commands</emphasis> will be use for deploying the application are: <command>git</command>,
	<command>docker</command> and <command>docker-compose</command>.</para>
	
	<section>
		
		<title>Importing Bitnami Virtual Machine</title>
		<para> The first step is importing Bitnami Virtual Machine in your hypervisor in order to execute the commands required for the 
		application deployment.</para>
		<para>Start the Virtual Machine importation by selecting <literal>File->Import Service Virtualization</literal> then browse in your 
		local folders to find the Bitnami Virtual Machine file. Follow the steps of the wizard.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img001.png"/>
			</imageobject>
				<caption>
				<para>Importing virtual disk image</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<warning>
			<title>Warning</title>
			<para>Check out your network preferences in your machine in order to ensure that you have 
			the Ethernet network interfaces required (Adapter 1).</para>
		</warning>
		
		<para>Once you have import your virtual machine you will be able to start it.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img002.png"/>
			</imageobject>
				<caption>
				<para>Imported Virtual Machine</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		
		<title>Starting the server: check the IP Address</title>
		<para>Now you can start the server. Choose the Ubuntu OS selected by default, once the server is running you can access to the Bitnami
		Virtual Machine using the default user and password: bitnami/ bitnami.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img02b.png"/>
			</imageobject>
				<caption>
				<para>Starting the server</para>	
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img003.png"/>
			</imageobject>
				<caption>
				<para>Introducing Ubuntu login</para>	
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<para>Next step is <emphasis role="bold"> checking the IP Address</emphasis> of your localhost using the command 
		<command>ifconfig eth0</command></para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img004.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
			<para>ifconfig eth0: checking the IP Address</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<para>After that you must to add this IP Address into your local machine and a sample host. To do that you need to modify the 
		hosts file. This file is located on the following route:</para>
		<para><keycap>%SystemRoot%\System32\drivers\etc\hosts</keycap></para>
		
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>Note that you must have Administrator privileges to modify and save the changes on hosts file. Simply right click 
			in your notepad and select "Administrator" mode to open it. Then open hosts file from your notepad. 
			</para>
		</note>
		
		<para>Add in the last line your IP Address and your sample host. Save all the changes.</para>
		<para><keycap>IP_address    test.com</keycap></para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img005.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
			<para>Adding an IP Address and a sample host to your local machine</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		
		<title>Cloning bitnami-docker-ownCloud repository</title>
		<para>In order to get the packages required (latest ownCloud image and its requirements and MariaDB database) 
		you must clone the bitnami-docker-ownCloud repository. </para>
		<para>Execute the following command: <command>git clone https://github.com/bitnami/bitnami-docker-owncloud</command></para>
		
		<note>
			<title>Tips</title>
			<para>The up and down arrow keys allow you to see all the commands that you will need for this installation process</para>
		</note>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img006.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
			<para>git clone: cloning the bitnami-docker-ownCloud repository</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		
		<title>Configuring environment variables</title>
		<para>For configuring environment variables you must modify the <keycap>docker-compose</keycap> file.</para>
		<para>Execute <command>vi docker-compose.yml</command></para>
		
		<note>
			<title>Tips</title>
			<para>This file will be opened in Vim text editor. For insert a new line press <keycap>I</keycap>.</para>
			<para>Once the enviroment has been added you can save the chanches pressing <keycap>Esc</keycap> and write <keycap>:wq</keycap></para>
		</note>
		
		<para>For docker-compose add the variable name and value under the application section:</para>
		
		<para><command>
			application:
			  image: 'bitnami/owncloud:latest'
              ports:
                - '80:80'
                - '443:443'
              environment:
                - 'OWNCLOUD_HOST=your_host'
              volumes:
                - 'owncloud_data:/bitnami/owncloud'
                - 'apache_data:/bitnami/apache'
                - 'php_data:/bitnami/php'
		</command></para>
		
		<para>You can also copy this docker-compose file and add the variable name and value under the application section: 
		<ulink url="https://github.com/bitnami/bitnami-docker-owncloud/blob/master/docker-compose.yml/"></ulink></para>
		
		<warning>
			<title>Warning</title>
			<para>In order to avoid possible issues we recommend to add the IP Address instead the sample host.</para>
		</warning>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img008.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
			<para>Configuring environment variables: add the IP Address for your application</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>	
		
	</section>
	
    <section>
		
		<title>Run the Docker containers</title>
		<para>Once you´ve modified the docker-compose file you are able to run the containers. To do that simply execute the 
		<command>docker-compose up</command> command.</para>
		<para>Both containers one for MariaDB database and ownCloud application will be updated. Don´t perform any action during this 
		process:</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img009.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
			<para>Running Docker containers: your containers are updated</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<para>If you want to run the containers manually, please, check the folowing links:</para> 
		<para><ulink url="https://docs.docker.com/"></ulink></para>
		<para><ulink url="https://github.com/bitnami/bitnami-docker-owncloud/"></ulink></para>	
		
    </section>
    
    <section>
		
		<title>Visiting your application</title>
		<para>Now everything is ready for visiting you application introducing your IP Address (the same that you added both in
		your hosts file and in docker-compose file as enviroment) in your browser.</para>
		<para>You should see ownCloud login interface. You can access your application using the default user and password: 
		<literal>user/ bitnami.</literal></para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img010.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
			<para>Visiting your application</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<section>
			
			<title>Untrusted domains</title>
			<para>Sometimes when you are trying to access the application, ownCloud identify it as an untrusted domain.</para>
			
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch02_img011.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
				<para>Visiting your application: ownCloud untrusted domain</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			
		<para>You have two options for configuring your domain as a trusted domain for ownCloud:</para>
		
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
			<listitem>
				<para>Click the button <literal>Add IP_Adress as a trusted domain</literal> in the login interface.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Use <literal>bnconfig tool</literal> in your ownCloud installation.</para>
				<para>Check out how to modify ownCloud the untrusted domains following the links below:</para>
				<para><ulink url="https://wiki.bitnami.com/Applications/BitNami_ownCloud#How_to_modify_the_ownCloud_trusted_domains.3f/"></ulink></para>
				<para><ulink url="https://doc.owncloud.org/server/7.0/admin_manual/configuration/config_sample_php_parameters.html#default-config-php-examples/"></ulink></para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		
		</section>
		
    </section>
    
</chapter>
