<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "manual.ent">
<!ENTITY PRODUCT "Documentation">
<!ENTITY BOOKID "manual">
<!ENTITY YEAR "2016">
<!ENTITY HOLDER "Bitnami. |">
]>
<chapter>
	
	<title>Getting starting with ownCloud</title>
	<para>Once you have updated the containers you can access the application typing the IP Address in your browser. 
	You will see the login interface. Usethe default user and password <literal>user/ bitnami.</literal></para> 
	
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img001.png"/>
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>owCloud login screen</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
		
	<para>the ownCloud Web interface opens to your Files page. You can add, remove, and share files, and make changes 
	based on the access privileges you have. (In this case as server administrator).</para>
	
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img002.png"/>
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>owCloud main user interface</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	
	<section>
		
		<title>Options and fuctions in the ownCloud main user interface</title>
		<para>In the main user interface you can find the following areas for navigating ownCloud:</para>
		
		<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Files options menu:</emphasis> You can find it in the upper left menu. Click the arrow
				to see the options availables.
				</para>
				<para>
					-Favourites
				</para>
				<para>
					-Shared with you
				</para>
				<para>
					-Shared with others
				</para>
				<para>
					-Shared by links
				</para>
				<para>
					-Tags
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Application Settings:</emphasis> In the bottom left menu you can access to the application settings and 
				to the list of deleted files. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Folders and files:</emphasis> The main central area displays all the items and user features.
				</para>		
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Navigation menu:</emphasis> Located at top margin it includes the following options.
					<para><literal>-new</literal> button: enables you to create new files, new folders, or upload files</para> 
					<para>Gallery button: four squares icon that enables you to display your images gallery.</para>  
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Search field:</emphasis> Located at top right margin, allows you to search files quickly.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">User settings:</emphasis> Open the dropdown menu for display your personal settings. 
					This menu contains the following settings and features:
				</para>
				<para>-Personal: you can set your personal info, sync clients, user and application passwords and monitoring your 
				recent activity and sessions.</para>
				<para>-Users: select this option for creating new groups and configuring their credentials and storage quota amongst 
				other actions.</para>
				<para>-Help</para>
				<para>-Admin: here you can view your security and setup warnings.</para>
				<para>-Log Out: click here to log out the application.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img003.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Fields and functions in ownCloud user interface</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<para>The following sections explain how to do the main basic operations in ownCloud such as files and folders creation, 
		uploadig/ downloading files or change user´s passwords.</para>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>How to create new folders?</title>
		<para>You can create folders and new text files both directly from the main user interface and within an existing folder. 
		You simply must use in both cases the <literal>New</literal> button.</para>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Creating a folder in the root directory:</emphasis> click the <literal>new</literal> button and select the 
		folder option.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img004.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Creating a new folder in the main user interface</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Creating a new folder inside an existing folder:</emphasis> click on the folder you want to create the 
		new folder or text file and once you have accessed, click click the <literal>new</literal> button and select the 
		folder option.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img005.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Creating a new folder inside an existing folder</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
			
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Uploading and downloading folders and files</title>
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Uploading files</emphasis>
		<footnote><para>This option is not available for folder upload. You can compress your folder
		and upload it as a compressed file into your application.</para></footnote>
		is very simple in ownCloud. Simply click on <literal>New</literal> button both in
		the main user interface and inside an existing folder and select the <literal>Upload</literal> option. Select the file from your computer
		and click Open. It will be automatically added to your application.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img006.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Uploading files</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<para><emphasis role="bold">Downloading files </emphasis></para>
		<para>For downloading files you have two options:</para>
		
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
		<listitem>
			<para>Select the item you want to download and then click on the vertical bar with three little circles
		that is located on the right of each file/ foldername. It opens a dropdown menu: select the <literal>Download</literal> option.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Make a single or a multiple selection clicking the checkbox and select the <literal>Download</literal> option that is located
			on top of the content list.</para>
		</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img007.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Downloading files/ folders</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		 
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>If you are downloading a folder this will be downloaded as a compressed file.</para>	
		</note>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		
		<title>How to share files and folders</title>
		<para>You can share files with other groups or by getting the local link of each item.</para>
		<para>Clicking on <literal>Share</literal> icon (on the right of file or foldername) you can introduce the name of the 
		groups to share it with and also get its local link.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img009.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Sharing files/ folders</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>Remember, you can check the files or folders shared with you, shared with others or shared by link
			in the options you can find in the Files Options Menu.</para>
		</note>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img010.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>View shared files</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Renaming files and see details</title>
		<para>You can rename your folders and files at anytime and check the history of the item and other detais as related tags
		or sharings.</para>
		<para>Find <literal>Details</literal> and <literal>Rename</literal> options in the dropdown menu beside the folders.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img011.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Rename and Details options</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img012.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Details</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	
	</section>
    
    <section>
		<title>Delete files and folders</title>
		<para>For deleting files you have two options:</para>
		
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
		<listitem>
			<para>Select the item you want to delete and then click on the vertical bar with three little circles
		that is located on the right of each file/ foldername. It opens a dropdown menu: select the <literal>Delete</literal> option.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Make a single or a multiple selection clicking the checkbox and select the <literal>Delete</literal> option that is displayed
		    in the Navigation Menu.</para>
		</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img013.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Deleting files</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>You can view all deleted files simply by clicking <literal>Deleted files</literal> option in the Application 
			Settings Menu.</para>
			<para>This screen shows you all files that were deleted and gives you the option of recovering them.</para>
		</note>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img014.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Recovering files</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>How can I change my password?</title>
		<para>In the <emphasis role="bold">Users Settings Menu</emphasis> you can find the following options: Personal and Users.</para>
		<para><emphasis>Personal</emphasis> allows you to change your personal password and set your application password.</para>
		<para><emphasis>Users</emphasis> option enables you to set the Users Groups privileges and also create and change their users and 
		passwords.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img015.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Change personal password</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img016.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Change Users Group password</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Checking if my version is updated</title>
		<para>You can check if you currently have the latest stable version of ownCloud in <literal>Users Settings-> Administration.</literal></para>
		<para>In this section you access to several options for configuring your preferences.</para>
		
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata scalefit="1" align="center" width="350" fileref="images/ch03_img017.png"/>
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>Check the latest version of ownCloud</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	
</chapter>
